http://www.systweak.com/privacy-policy

Systweak Privacy Policy
We believe you have the right to secure and control your information and this credence is what helped us create our Privacy Policy.
Privacy Policy
When do we gather your data?
What data do we Collect?
How we gather your data?
How personal data is used?
Omissions
Added Privacy Contemplations
Revisions
Last Updated: January 31, 2019
We believe you (user) have the right to secure and control your information and this credence is what helped us create our Privacy Policy.
We will be transparent with you about why and how we collect data. In no manner we will sell your data to any third party. Our main aim of data collection is to provide you with the services and software that you expect from us as company to deliver.
This Privacy Policy implements to Systweak’s website and all its products. It describes how Systweak shares, gathers, uses, and locks your personal data. It even defines your choice about use, entry, and modification to your personal details (if any).
If you have any recommendations or queries, feel free to contact us at privacypolicy@systweak.com.
Caution: Legal content ahead.
When do we gather your data?
We may gather information from you: (1) when license of our product is purchased and used ("Software Collection"); (2) when our website is visited be it, blogs, support center and others ("Website Collection"); and (3) when you interact with us either by email, live chat, or other means ("Dialogue Collection").
In Simple Words: We gather your data when you visit our website, use applications, or connect with us by any means.
What data do we Collect?
We may gather personal data from you like contact information (name, email address, or phone number); along with other unique identifiers (username & password for Systweak products and accounts). For businesses owning Systweak products, we may collect business information (company name, size, business type etc.) and any information related to use of Systweak product, explained in the following section.
In addition, billing information such as credit card details and billing address may be accumulated by our third-party service, to process orders on our behalf.
Non-personal data stands for details that do not show your identity directly, or after being changed when combined with other data. We do gather some information automatically like Internet protocol (IP) addresses, referral/exit pages, operating system, Internet service provider (ISP), date/time stamp, browser type, files watched on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), clickstream data. This all is collected to study marketing trends, and generate device identifiers secretly to manage the site.
In Simple Words: We collect two categories of information: - personal and impersonal.
Details we may collect when you use our software
User-Agent String
You can check information about our software through the API communication string. The user-agent string displays the following details.
The database and program sending the request.
The recent license state (as approved by the product).
The version of the software, as well as any sub-components (current, databases) that it uses.
Why? To manage your purchased Systweak product and to make sure you are running an up to date product.
GeoIP Data
We don’t save IP address of our users, during any data collection from our clients. However, this data is used to collect topographical information of the system from which the request is made:
Location code based on the IP address, to stand for continent, city, country, and estimated latitude/ longitude of the user.
Type of network connection whether broadband/mobile/satellite.
ISP used to setup connection.
Name of organization if using licensed IP address.
Why? This helps security team at Systweak to find potentially unwanted programs ("PUP") and malware attacks and ways.
Functional Data
Only the essential information needed to enhance product performance is gathered. For instance, information like system processes and actions help to perform recovery operations like system restore.
Why? To make Systweak products perform as user wants and to efficiently deal with malware, PUP and give restore and recovery operations.
Consumer Data
Furthermore, we collect consumer data that defines environment (i.e., software, information of the PC it is installed on.) This consists of following information:
Details of operating system the program is running on.
Language of the operating system.
Processor architecture (i.e., 32- or 64-bit).
File system in use (NTFS or FAT).
Data from Windows Security/Action Center, including security settings and security programs, applications installed or running.
Details about other malware products, their settings and configuration.
Log data, stored information about how you use our product.
Why? This collected information helps to know how the product functions in conjunction with hardware and software environments. By getting all these details, we can optimize and improve products performance on various platform with different system configuration.
Identification Data of Machine
At the time of product installation Systweak generates a distinct identifier to recognize the machine.
Why? To get exact number of installations and to recognize changes made to the system over a period. This allows to identify trends that helps to improve Systweak products.
License Data
The data is gathered from registered products and includes a unique identifier. We collect following information in this:
Registration code or code used to activate the product in use.
Kind of license in use.
If it stands for single or multiple use.
Why? To inform the user when product key will end or to check the correct license key. Such registration data may be used in combination with other software data to aid you in solving registration matters.
Infectious File Data
Information about malware and PUPs detected by our product is collected. This includes:
Merchant name of the malware or PUP deleted.
Database description use to remove PUP or the threat in question.
Items found as PUPs, malware, or doubtful files.
Data linked to detected objects.
Why? To help intelligence team at Systweak trail PUP outbursts and develop more efficient products.
Trial Data
When a user attempts to use trial version of the product we track the request remotely to know if trial is permitted on his machine or not. For this we use different unique system identifier and collect information:
User’s request for using trial version of the product.
Start date and allowed duration for the trial period.
Any attempt made to buy the product generate through an in-app link, to know if it is generated from within the trial version.
Why? To update installed Systweak products precisely and when needed.
Activity Data
When security products are used, complex data object is collected to for the products that are blocked by the software. The collected data includes:
Process ID of the process.
File path of the blocked process.
MD5 hash of the detected file, if any.
Command-line arguments passed.
All details related malware including URLs and redirect jumps if any.
Data shared over the Internet.
File-format (doc, xls, etc…).
(Possibly) a copy of the malicious executable file itself.
Why? To understand and track exploit outbreak and to create new security techniques to handle exploit techniques.
Cell Phone Application Data
When our services are used or downloaded, we automatically collect information like device type, version of operating system and information about unique device identifier.
Also, push notifications are sent from time- to-time to update user about any updates or upgrades that may be running. If at any time user decides not to receive these notifications he can disable them at the device level. Therefore, to make sure you receive prompt notifications, we need to gather device information like user identification details and operating system information.
However, at no point we ask, track or access location information from user’s cell phone when our applications are downloaded or any services are used. For this we use analytics software that help us understand our products functionality better. This analytics software may record information like how often the application is used, how it works on your device, from where the application was downloaded and others. In no manner we link this saved information with any persona data you share using mobile application.
As a share of text message sifting functionality, our anti malware product does not collect or save any information, it simple scans the URL received in the message when you access them.
In Simple Words: All this information is collected to safeguard your device from malware and PUPs and send them push notifications when permitted.
Website and Dialogue Collection
For this we gather and ask user to give away information about himself but not limited to:
Communication details, like your name, email address, address.
User ID and password, if an account is created at Systweak.
Chat and team viewer information, you share when communicating with our team.
Device information, including browser name and traffic details.
Why? However, it is not obligatory to share this data, but for functioning of certain services or to access customer support all this information may be needed. In absence of data we may fail to deliver the requested services properly.
How we gather your data?
Directly
Some information is given out directly when comments are posted, questions are asked on the blog, user profile is created or you willingly allow the support agent to remotely login or access your system. Also, we may collect or store all the information posted on blog, user profile and make them viewable publicly.
In Simple Words: We gather your information when you provide it on our blog or on customer support portal.
Cookies
We and our partners gather information via "cookies" enabled in the browser and use other alike tracking technologies to study trends, track users' activity on the website, and collect statistical data about website visitors, manage the website. As we know cookies is a small text file stored by the web browser when enabled via settings. Session cookies and persistent cookies may be used to know you have logged in, when and how our website and services are used, and to check usage and traffic on the website.
When you close the browser, or log out from the account, session cookies automatically get removed. At any time, you can stop site from saving cookies but doing same may not allow you to access our software and services completely.
In Simple Words: When you visit the site, we collect information using cookies, at any time you can stop this, by disabling cookies from the web browser.
Account Registration
If an account is created using support page, you need to share username to confirm identity.
In Simple Words: The information is collected when you create an account.
Software Functionality
The software installed on your machine collects data transfer information between the machine and software at our server. This is to ensure our software is working properly and to know activation status of the software.
Simple Words: We gather information about Systweak product license.
How personal data is used?
Directly
Apart from the exclusions explained below, no personal details is shared with third parties. The collected information is used only to enhance our product and market them.
In Simple Words: With few omissions listed below, we do not share any of your information with third parties.
Omissions
Website Analytics
Our servers automatically store information about use of products and services under log data information. This may include information about user's operating system, browser, Internet Protocol (IP) address, web page used, using which the request is sent to our server, URL of the visited page, search term, product page along with how long user has been on that page. For this and to analyze data Google Analytics is used, to know about Google's privacy policy visit:
https://policies.google.com/privacy.
In Simple Words: Omission #1: We do share with website interaction with Google analytics for analysis purpose.
Third-Party Service Providers
We may use third party services to manage and offer our services. For this certain personal data may be shared with them so that services can be executed on our behalf, like to make a product purchase, process payments, deliver updates, send communications based on marketing trends, research and analysis and provide cloud computing environment. The third parties with whom information is shared, agree upon not sharing your personal details or using it for any other purposes.
Amazon Web Services is used for cloud based product, as it offers strict security and privacy features, including ISO and SOC certificates. For more information on how the service works visit: https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/ .
In Simple Words: Omission #2: Information shared with third party companies, is not used anywhere else besides, our business.
Business Transactions
All collected information from the user including personal data is considered as an asset. Hence, if at any given point of time we are acquired because of merger, or any other reason your information will be showed or shared with the third-party acquirer in connection with the transaction. You will be informed for the change of ownership via email/ prior notice will be given and choice you may have about sharing of personal data.
In Simple Words: Omission #3: If there is a merger or someone buys our company then your data will be shared with that someone else.
Legislative; Law Enforcement
We reserve the right to use or disclose any information we collect without notice or consent as required to satisfy any law, regulation or legal request; to conduct investigations of consumer complaints or possible breaches of law; to protect the integrity of our site and our property; to protect the safety of our visitors or others; to fulfill your requests; or to cooperate in any legal investigation.
In certain situations, we may show your personal data to public authorities with a legal request to enhance national security and law enforcement.
In Simple Words: Omission #4: If any legal agency or government asks to share your information we will be compelled to share.
Permission
If you specifically mention to share your personal data with third-party sites or platforms, like social networking sites, we may do so.
Likewise, when a profile, content, or other details are posted, that includes your personal data, you agree on using these details publicly. Also, you should be conscious of the fact that any information shared in these areas may be read, gathered, or used by others who have access to them. You will be listed on our publicly open blog/website.
In addition to other recommendations, this we will display testimonials received from pleased customers on our website. With your permission we may display your testimonial along with your name. However, if you wish to change, delete your testimonial, you can contact us at privacypolicy@systweak.com
In Simple Words: Omission #5: Information posted by you (if any) on the blog/website is public.
Added Privacy Contemplations
Legalities of using personal data.
The General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 ("GDPR"), effective May 25, 2018. GDPR mandates that personal data should only be process under a legal binding. The legal binding may differ depending on the country or jurisdiction. Details for legalities that we follow when using your data are listed below.
In Simple Words: We use these legalities for processing data subject to the GDPR.
Contract of performance
Your personal data will be used in accordance to the agreement we have. To explain let’s take an example: to purchased, register and maintain your account we will make sure that the product functions in a secure way and responds to your requests.
Sincere interests
Your personal data may be used for our sincere interests. For example, we trust our legal interests to analyze and improve our products, content on the website, to send you information about product update or information related to products or use of your information for legal purpose, administrative and fraud detection.
Legal implications
Your personal data may be used to follow legal requirements, as explained in omission 4, above.
Consent
At certain occasions we may seek your consent to perform certain action using your personal data. When doing so we will be transparent about sharing your details so that you are aware of what you are agreeing to.
Choice
We have partnership with third parties to manage and display our advertisement on other sites. For this they may use cookies or likewise technologies to show advertisement based on your browsing activities and interests. However, if you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click here [or if located in the European Union click here ]. Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.
To receive email, newsletter, or other communications from us you can sign up. But once you communicate with us by downloading a product or by visiting our website you may be added to the mailing list. However, if you want to stop receiving any information from us you can use the “Unsubscribe” link sent in the mails or you can contact us at privacypolicy@systweak.com.
Report Detected Infections
You may opt out of sample collection in certain Systweak products by using the steps mentioned below. These samples are collected to analysis malware infected files detected on your machine.
In Simple Words: We give you all the control to manage your data.
Using Advanced System Protector for Home on Windows:
Launch Advanced System Protector
Here, click on Quarantine tab > Logs.
At the bottom of the screen uncheck “Yes, I want to improve Advanced System Protector, by allowing it to report detected infections to servers.”
Once you do so, no longer the infectious file will be sent to our servers.
Security
We take all necessary security measures to protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use and leak. However, there is no fully secure method to store or send data over Internet, therefore, we cannot guarantee complete security of your personal data.
In Simple Words: We do all that is necessary to secure your data.
Retaining
We may keep your personal data as needed to carry out the purpose for which it was collected. Your personal data may be used to fulfill our business needs, legal duties, protection of assets, and implement our agreements. These needs may vary depending on the product or service.
In Simple Words: We keep your personal data only to support our product and for the reason it is collected.
Links
Our website may encompass link to some third-party websites, if you give any information on these links then the owner of that site will be directly responsible for your privacy. Before sharing any information, you should read terms and conditions of that site as we will not handle the content, privacy, or security of that site and services.
In Simple Words: Our privacy policy is applied only till the time you are on our site, if you visit a third-party site we will not be responsible.
Updating or Removal of your personal data
To know what all data we may have about you, contact us by sending email to privacypolicy@systweak.com. Besides, if you want to delete the information you can contact us at privacypolicy@systweak.com we will respond to you in a realistic timeframe and will delete your personal data. However, some information may be kept in backup copies for our record or as needed by the law. We may keep your information for as long as you use the services or your account is active, to deal with legal responsibilities and to resolve arguments and apply our agreements.
In Simple Words: Subjected to law we will delete or alter your information if asked.
International
Your personal data may be transferred to, and maintained on, computers located outside of your state, province, country, or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide your personal data to us, we may transfer your personal data to the United States and process it there.
Systweak participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Systweak is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries, in reliance on the Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework's applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce's
Privacy Shield List.
Systweak is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Systweak complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including the onward transfer liability provisions.
With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Systweak is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Systweak may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield.
Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website, you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.
In Simple Words: If you're not in the U.S., we may transfer your information to the U.S. We participate in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.
Children
We do not collect any personal data knowingly about children under thirteen. Our services are not designed for children under eighteen. However, we learn that any personal data of an adolescent is collected we will delete all such information from our files ASAP. But this information may still be in our record as backup copies or as otherwise required by the law.
In Simple Words: We do not collect children information intentionally, and if collected accidently we do delete it.
Revisions
We may alter or revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If any material changes are made to this policy we will inform you by showing notification on the website or by sending email or other notification before bringing change into effect.
In Simple Words: If we revise our privacy policy we will inform you. If any material changes are made to the policy, we will let you know before making the changes.
x
We use own and third-party cookies to show personalized content and ads on Systweak’s properties and other
sites, to provide social media features, to create an anonymous profile based on browsing behavior (visited
pages, frequency, time) and to analyze how our services are used. By clicking on the site, you accept their
use- More Info
Yes  or  No
Systweak Antivirus
Real-Time Protection For Your Computer.
Highly rated virus detection capabilities
Detects viruses without false flaggings
Prevent hacker infiltration with ease
Prevent and recover from identity theft.
Surf the web safely and anonymously
Download Now
Subscribe newsletter
Get a FREE App
in your email!
The Systweak Newsletter includes the latest and greatest offers. Get the best offers, deals and discount coupons before anyone else! You will get a free product in your email as soon as you subscribe and verify your email address. So get going, subscribe now!
Subscribe Now
Close Now
Subscribe Newsletter
x
Please enter your name
Please enter your email address
Subscribe Now
